<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">English Workbook</string>
    <string name="syntax_one_instruction">Introduction:</string>
    <string name="syntax_one_instruction_content">Are you ready to embark on a journey that\'ll make you a Sentence wizard? \n\nUnderstanding sentence structure is like learning how to construct a skyscraper or design a video game—it\'s all about putting pieces together in the most awesome way possible. \n\nThis workbook will equip you with the skills to craft sentences! \n\nSo, let\'s dive in! \n\nSentence structure refers to the arrangement and organization of words, phrases, and clauses in a sentence. \n\nUnderstanding sentence structure is crucial for effective communication, both in written and spoken form. \n\nVaried sentence structures make your writing more engaging and easier to understand. \n\nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully \nEN7G-II-a-1</string>
    <string name="quizzes_syntax_one">Read each sentence carefully. \n\nSelect the best answer that identifies the type of sentence based on its structure.</string>
    <string name="sysntaxOneOne">Simple Sentence \n\nCarries a singular idea, emotion, or piece of information. \n\nAt its heart, it has one independent clause (subject and predicate), which means the sentence can stand alone and still make complete sense. \n\nExamples: \n\nSentence: We fixed the computer. \nComplete Subject: We \nComplete Predicate: fixed the computer. \n\nSentence: Allan and Miko played sepak takraw. \nComplete Subject: Allan and Miko \nComplete Predicate: played sepak takraw. \n\nSentence: Most students come from rural areas. \nComplete Subject: Most students \nComplete Predicate: come from rural areas.</string>
    <string name="sysntaxOneTwo">Compound Sentence \n\nAllows you to link thoughts together using coordinating conjunctions like \'and\', \'but\', \'or\', \'yet\', \'so\', \'nor\', and \'for\'. \n\nThis is achieved by using two main clauses in one sentence. \n\nExamples: \n\nSentence: Habibi was elected as President and Marje became secretary. \nMain Clause 1: Habibi was elected as President \nCoordinating Conjunction: and \nMain Clause 2: Marje became secretary. \n\nSentence: Some students love English but others prefer Science. \nMain Clause 1: Some students love English \nCoordinating Conjunction: but \nMain Clause 2: others prefer Science.</string>
    <string name="syntaxOneThree">Complex Sentence \n\nShows a relationship between ideas by connecting one main clause and one or more subordinating clauses. \n\nA subordinating clause, unlike a main one, cannot stand alone. \n\nCommon subordinating conjunctions that often introduce subordinating clauses are: \'although\', \'because\', \'if\', \'since\', \'when\', \'while\', and many more. \n\nExamples: \n\nSentence: When the moon shines, the ocean glows. \nSubordinating Conjunction + Subordinating Clause: When the moon shines, \nMain Clause: the ocean glows. \n\nSentence: Because my sister sings, she joined the choir. \nSubordinating Conjunction + Subordinating Clause: Because my sister sings, \nMain Clause: she joined the choir.</string>
    <string name="syntaxOneFour">Compound-Complex Sentence \n\nIncludes at least two independent clauses and one or more dependent clauses. \n\nExamples: \n\nSentence: When the moon shines, the ocean glows, and the world feels magical. \nSubordinating Conj. + Subordinating Clause: When the moon shines, \nMain Clause 1: the ocean glows, \nCoordinating Conjunction: and \nMain Clause 2: the world feels magical. \n\nSentence: Although my sister sings, she doesn\’t dance, but she plays the guitar. \nSubordinating Conj. + Subordinating Clause: Although my sister sings, \nMain Clause 1: she doesn\’t dance, \nCoordinating Conjunction: but \nMain Clause 2: she plays the guitar. </string>
    <string name="syntaxt_two_instruction">Understanding the different types of sentences is crucial for effective communication and writing. \n\nSentences can serve various functions, conveying information, asking questions, expressing emotions, or issuing commands. \n\nIn this workbook, we will explore the four main types of sentences according to their functions. \n\nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully \nEN7G-II-a-1</string>
    <string name="syntax_three_three">Objects in Sentences \n\n1. Direct Object \n\nIt receives the action directly or complete the meaning of a verb and answer the questions: \“What?\” or \“Whom?\” \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: \"She takes the book to the office.\" \nDirect Object: \"book\" (receives the action directly) \n\n2. Indirect Objects \n\nIndirect objects receive the action indirectly and answers \"to whom\" or \"for whom\" the action is done. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: \"The clerk issued us receipts.\" \nIndirect Object: \"us\" (answers \"to whom\" the receipts were issued)</string>
    <string name="syntaxt_two_one">Declarative Sentences \n\nUsed to make statements, provide information, or express facts. \n\nThey serve the primary function of conveying information or declaring something. \n\nDeclarative sentences typically end with a period (.), and they are the most common sentence type in written and 	spoken language. \n\nExamples: \n\nThe sun rises in the east. \n\nShe is an excellent student. \n\nThe cat is sleeping on the couch.</string>
    <string name="syntaxt_two_two">Interrogative Sentences \n\nDesigned to ask questions and seek information. \n\nThey are used to elicit responses or engage in conversations. \n\nInterrogative sentences can begin with words like who, what, when, where, why, and how, and they end with a question mark (?). \n\nExamples: \n\nWhat time does the movie start? \n\nWhere is the nearest grocery store? \n\nHow did you solve the math problem?</string>
    <string name="syntaxt_two_three">Imperative Sentences \n\nUsed to give commands, make requests, or offer suggestions. \n\nThey are intended to 	influence others to take specific actions. \n\nImperative sentences often do not include a subject (it\'s implied), and they usually end with a period (.) or an exclamation mark (!) for strong emphasis. \n\nExamples: \n\nPlease pass me the salt. (request) \n\nClose the door. (command) \n\nLet\'s go to the park! (suggestion)</string>
    <string name="syntaxt_two_four">Exclamatory Sentences \n\nUsed to express strong emotions, enthusiasm, surprise, or excitement. \n\nThey convey a heightened emotional state and often begin with words like what or how and end with an exclamation mark (!). \n\nExamples:	\n\nWhat a beautiful sunset! \n\nHow amazing that concert was! \n\nI can\'t believe we won!</string>
    <string name="syntax_three_instruction">Welcome to the exciting world of sentences! \n\nIn this lesson, we\'re going on a journey to uncover the fascinating parts that make up sentences. \n\nJust like a treasure hunt, we\'ll discover subjects, predicates, objects, and modifiers that will help you become a sentence expert. \n\nIt\'s like learning the magic behind your favorite tricks! \n\nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully \nEN7G-II-a-1</string>
    <string name="syntax_three_one">Subjects and Predicates \n\nIn every sentence, there are two key parts: the subject and the predicate. \n\nThe subject is the part that tells us what the sentence is about, and it\'s usually a noun or pronoun. \n\nThe predicate, on the other hand, is the part that tells us what the subject is doing or what\'s happening. \n\nIt includes the verb and other words that describe the action. \n\nTo find the subject and predicate in such sentences, look for the main noun or pronoun and the main verb. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: \"The students go to school every day.\" \nSubject: \"students\" (refers to the person performing the action) \nPredicate: \"go\" (action that was done) \n\nSentence: \"Juan brought boiled sweet potatoes for snacks.\" \nSubject: \"Juan\" (refers to the animal performing the action) \nPredicate: \"brought\" (the action that was done)</string>
    <string name="syntax_three_two">Types of Subjects and Predicates \n\n1. Subjects and Predicates \n\n1a. Simple Subjects and Simple Predicates \n\nSimple subjects are the main nouns or pronouns in a sentence, while simple predicates are the main verbs. \n\nThey form the core of a sentence. \n\nExamples: \n\nSentence: The sun rises early. \nSimple Subject: sun \nSimple Predicate: rises \n\nSentence: The baby cries in the crib. \nSimple Subject: baby \nSimple Predicate: cries \n\n1b. Complete Subjects and Complete Predicates \n\nComplete Subjects are composed of a noun or a noun phrase being talked about in the sentence plus all its modifiers, while complete predicates are composed of a verb or a verb phrase that tells something about the subject, plus all its modifiers. \n\nExamples: \n\nSentence: The awful incident keeps on haunting his memory. \nComplete Subject: The awful incident \nComplete Predicate: keeps on haunting his memory. \n\nSentence: That lady in red started all the gossip. \nComplete Subject: That lady in red \nComplete Predicate: started all the gossip. \n\n2. Compound Subjects and Compound Predicates \n\nCompound subjects and compound predicates involve more than one subject or verb, adding complexity to sentences. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: John and Jane arrange the enrolment forms of the students alphabetically and sort them according to their enrolled grade level. \nCompound Subject: John and Jane \nCompound Predicate: arrange the enrolment forms of the students alphabetically and sort them according to their enrolled grade level.</string>
    <string name="syntax_three_four">Object of the Preposition \n\nThe object of a preposition is a noun or pronoun that follows a preposition (like \"on,\" \"in,\" \"at\") and adds details to the sentence, usually about location or direction. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: \"The book is on the table.\" \nObject of the Preposition: \"table\" (provides information about the location)</string>
    <string name="syntax_three_five">Modifiers in Sentences \n\n1. Adjectives \n\nThese are words that describe or modify nouns or pronouns, adding details and qualities. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: \"The tall, green tree stands proudly.\" \nAdjectives: \"tall\" and \"green\" (modify the noun \"tree\") \n\n2. Adverbs \n\nThese are words that modify verbs, adjectives, or other adverbs. \n\nThey tell us how, when, where, or to what extent something happens. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: \"She ran quickly and gracefully.\" \nAdverbs: \"quickly\" and \"gracefully\" (modify the verb \"ran\")</string>
    <string name="syntax_four_instruction">Effective communication and proficient writing depend on your ability to construct sentences that convey ideas clearly and eloquently. \n\nIn this lesson, we will delve into the intricate world of sentence patterns, providing you with a solid foundation to enhance your writing skills. \n\nWhether you\'re a seventh grader just beginning your journey or a tenth grader refining your craft, this workbook is designed to cater to learners at various stages of proficiency. \n\nAt its core, a sentence pattern is the arrangement of words in a sentence to convey a complete thought. \n\nIt serves as the blueprint that guides the organization of subjects, verbs, objects, adjectives, adverbs, and other elements within a sentence. \n\nSentence patterns dictate the structure and flow of your writing, influencing how effectively your ideas are communicated. \n\nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully \nEN7G-II-a-1</string>
    <string name="syntax_four_one">Subject-Verb (SV) \n\nThe SV pattern consists of a subject and a verb. \n\nIt\'s the simplest sentence structure. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: The cat sleeps. \nSubject: The cat \nVerb: sleeps (the action or state)</string>
    <string name="syntax_four_two">Subject-Verb-Object (SVO) \n\nThe SVO pattern includes a subject, a verb, and an object. \n\nThe subject performs the action on the object. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: The dog chases the ball. \nSubject: The dog \nVerb: chases \nObject: the ball. (the entity receiving the action)</string>
    <string name="syntax_four_three">Subject-Verb-Adjective (SVAdj) \n\nThe SVAdj pattern contains a subject, a verb, and an adjective that describes the subject. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: The sky is blue. \nSubject: The sky \nVerb: is \nAdjective: blue (describes the subject)</string>
    <string name="syntax_four_four">Subject-Verb-Adverb (SVAdv) \n\nThe SVAdv pattern comprises a subject, a verb, and an adverb that modifies the verb. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: He runs quickly. \nSubject: He \nVerb: runs \nAdverb: quickly (modifies the verb)</string>
    <string name="syntax_four_five">Subject-Verb-Object-Complement (SVOC) \n\nThe SVOC pattern has a subject, a verb, an object, and a complement that provides additional information about the object. \n\nExample: \n\nSentence: She painted the wall red \nSubject: She \nVerb: painted \nObject: the wall \nComplement: red (Adds information about the object, specifying the color)</string>

    <string name="syntax_five_instruction">Welcome to the \"Exploring Phrases\" lesson! \n\nPhrases are essential building blocks of sentences, and a good grasp of phrases can greatly improve your writing and communication skills. \n\nA phrase is a group of related words that does not contain a subject and a predicate (verb and its accompanying elements) necessary for a complete sentence. \n\nPhrases function as units within sentences and can serve various grammatical roles. \n\nPhrases come in different types, including noun phrases, verb phrases, adjective phrases, and adverb phrases, each with its specific role and structure in a sentence. \n\nEN7G-II-a-1 \nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully. \n\nEN8WC-Id-1.1.6 \nOrganize ideas in one-step word, phrase, and sentence outline forms.</string>

    <string name="Noun">Noun Phrase \n\nIt is a word or group of words in a sentence that behaves in the same way as a noun, that is, as a subject, an object, a complement, or as the object of a preposition. \n\nExamples: \n\n1. \“A dark smoke scattered across the sky.\” \n\nIn this sentence, the noun phrase \“A dark smoke\” is functioning as the subject of the sentence. \n\n2. \“He spoke like an angel.\” \n\nIn this sentence, the noun phrase \“like an angel\” is an adverbial, because it functions as an adverb, describing how he spoke. \n\n3. \“The boxer threw a killing punch.\” \n\nHere, \“a killing punch\” is a noun phrase that functions as a direct object, being the thing that the boxer (the subject) threw (the verb). \n\n4. \“I baked my little brother a cake.\” \n\nThe noun phrase \“my little brother\” is the indirect object of the sentence, as it is affected by the verb but not the direct object of the verb, which is \“a cake.\” \n\n5. \“They both stayed in the top with exemplary marks.\” \n\nIn this sentence, the noun phrase \“in the top\” works as a prepositional phrase, because the noun \“top\” is modified by the preposition \“in.\” \n\n6. \“Some students lost their interest in doing well with their studies.\” \n\nThe noun phrase \“some students\” is a noun plus a determiner, meaning that the word \“some\” determines something essential about the noun. \n\nIn this case, it is a specific kind of determiner known as a quantifier, because it is revealing how many students lost their interest.</string>

    <string name="Verb">Verb Phrase \n\nIt is a combination of words that express an action or a state of being. \n\nIt typically consists of a main verb and one or more auxiliary verbs. \n\nVerb phrases are used to express complex ideas, such as opinions, feelings, and wishes. \n\nTypes of Verb Phrases \n\n1. Verb phrases with only the main verb \n\nWhen we hear the word \'phrase\', we expect the inclusion of more than one word; however, this isn\'t always the case! \n\nVerb phrases can be a singular main verb on its own. \n\nExamples: \n\nShe \"breaks\" her leg. \n\nThey both \"screamed.\" \n\nIn these examples, the verb phrase consists of a main verb only. \n\nThe verb can be in the present or past tense. \n\nThe first example is in the present tense and the second one is in the past tense. \n\n2. Auxiliary verb (to be) + main verb (-ing form) \n\nWhen the main verb is being used in its -ing form (e.g. walking, talking), it expresses a continuous aspect. \n\nThe use of auxiliary verbs will show whether the continuing action is in the past, present, or future. \n\nThe auxiliary verbs \"am\", \"is\", and \"are\" used before the main verb in \'-ing\' form creates the \"present continuous tense.\" \n\nThe auxiliary verbs was and were used before the main verb in \'-ing\' form creates the \"past continuous tense.\" \n\nThe combined auxiliary verbs \'will be\' used before the main verb in \'-ing\' form creates the \"future continuous tense.\" \n\nExamples: \n\nShe \"is staring\" at the window. \n\nThe students \"were writing\" their stories. \n\nJoan \"will be coming\" next day. \n\n3. Auxiliary verb (have) + main verb (past participle form) \n\nThis type of verb phrase includes the verb \'to have\' (including all of its forms e.g. have, has, had) and the past participle form of the main verb. \n\nPast participle verb forms are also referred to as verb 3. \n\nThey are most commonly used to show the perfect aspect, a verb form that shows an action is either completed or begun in the past. \n\nThe perfect aspect tends to focus more on the state of the action (i.e. whether or not it has been completed) rather than the action itself. \n\nFor example, \'It had just begun\' lets the listener know that the happening recently just begun. \n\nThe verbs \"have\" and \"has\" express a \"present perfect aspect\", whereas the verb \"had\" expresses a \"past perfect aspect.\" \n\nExamples: \n\nClaire had just slept for more than an hour. \n\nThe team has won the competition. \n\nRico had broken the window. \n\n4. Modal verb + main verb \n\nModal verbs are a type of auxiliary verb that express modality. \n\nModality includes things such as possibility, probability, ability, permission, ability, and obligation. \n\nExample modal verbs include: must, shall, will, should, would, can, could, may, and might. \n\nExamples: \n\nHe \"will join\" the singing contest. \n\nJess \"might deliver\" his speech later. \n\n5. Auxiliary verb (have + been) + main verb (-ing form) \n\nIn this case, both the continuous aspect and the perfect aspect are expressed. \n\nThe continuous aspect comes from the \'-ing\' verb, and the perfect aspect comes from the auxiliary verb \'have been\'. \n\nWhen the auxiliary verb \"has\" or \"have\" is used, it creates the \"present perfect continuous aspect\". \n\nWhen the auxiliary verb \"had\" is used, it expresses a \"past perfect continuous aspect.\" \n\nExamples: \n\nKrisha \"has been writing\" her poem. \n\nThe students \"had been reciting\" their speech.</string>

    <string name="Prepositional">Prepositional Phrase \n\n A prepositional phrase is a group of words that begins with a preposition (like \"under,\" \"in,\" or \"on\") and tells us more about the location of a noun or pronoun. \n\nIt is a combination of a preposition, a modifier and its object. \n\nA prepositional phrase can be placed in the beginning, middle or end of a sentence based on its role in that particular sentence. \n\nPrepositional phrases are just a part of the sentence it modifies and cannot stand alone. \n\nThere are a few points you have to keep in mind when using prepositional phrases. \n\nThey are: \n\n> Each sentence would require a different preposition to form a prepositional phrase. \n\n> Remember that using a wrong preposition can alter the meaning of the sentence completely and sometimes make no meaning at all. \n\n> If the prepositional phrase modifies a noun, it functions like an \"adjective\" and is therefore considered as an \"adjectival phrase.\" \n\n> Sometimes, a prepositional phrase is seen to modify the \"verb\" or action in the sentence and is considered as an \"adverbial phrase\" as it plays the role of an \"adverb\" in the sentence. \n\nExamples: \n\n\'Using Prepositional Phrases in the Beginning of the Sentence\' \n\n\"After sleeping for hours,\" Marina finally got the rest that her body wanted. \n\n\"Before the athletes start training,\" they would first conduct warm-up activities. \n\n\'Using Prepositional Phrases in the Middle of the Sentence\' \n\nThe man \"in the photograph\" is the one whom he was looking for. \n\nThe red bag \"on the cabinet\" was her favorite one. \n\n\'Using Prepositional Phrases in the End of the Sentence\' \n\nThe key was placed \"on the table.\" \n\nThey cut the tree \"beside our house.\"</string>

    <string name="Adjectival">Adjectival Phrase \n\nIt is a prepositional phrase that modifies noun or pronoun. \n\nExamples: \n\nThe students \"on that section\" are very noisy. \n\nThis cafe \"beside the mall\" has a good tasting coffee.</string>

    <string name="Adverbial">Adverbial Phrase \n\nIt is a prepositional phrase that modifies a verb, an adjective or an adverb. \n\nExamples:\n\nThe lady looks too chic \"on her dress.\" \n\nThe boy sat \"under the tree.\"</string>

    <string name="Infinitive">Infinitive Phrase \n\nAn infinitive phrase begins with the infinitive verb, usually with the word \"to\" in front. \n\nThe position of the infinitive phrase depends on the role it assumes in the sentence. \n\nIf the infinitive phrase displays the characteristics of a noun, it can be placed either in the beginning or end of the sentence. \n\nIn other words, it can either be the subject or the object of the sentence. \n\nIf the infinitive phrase performs as an adjective, it is most often placed just after the verb, and if it shows the characteristics of an adverb, it can be positioned in different parts of the sentence. \n\nFunctions of the Infinitive Phrase \n\nWhen an infinitive phrase functions as a \"noun\", it can be a subject, an object, or a complement. \n\nExamples: \n\n\"To win the contest\" was Kian’s only wish. \n\nHis only task was \"to feed the chicken every morning.\" \n\nInfinitive phrases can also act as \"adjectives.\" \n\nAn adjective describes or modifies a noun. \n\nExamples: \n\nI’m painting some landmarks \"to present on the exhibit.\" \n\nEvery day, Rico has the determination \"to do well in school.\" \n\nFinally, infinitive phrases can act like \"adverbs\" and modify a verb. \n\nUsually, when an infinitive phrase is functioning as an adverb, it explains the why of the verb. \n\nExamples: \n\nTrixie excels in school \"to make her parents proud.\" \n\nAhead of time, teacher Love prepared her lesson \"to avoid cramming.\"</string>

    <string name="Participial">Participial Phrase \n\nIt is a collection of words that begins with a present or past participle and functions as 	an adjective. \n\nIn simpler terms, it\'s a phrase that describes a noun or pronoun. \n\nThere are two kinds of participial phrases: Present participial phrases that use the present participle (-ing) form of a verb, and the past participial phrases that use the past participle (-d/-ed) form of a verb. \n\nPresent Participial Phrase \n\nIn English, present participles take the form of verbs ending in \"-ing.\" \n\nThis is the same form that verbs take in the present progressive tense. \n\nExamples: \n\n\"Talking about the incident,\" she said that she was not well aware of what exactly had happened. \n\n\"Fond of putting make up,\" the girl looked funny. \n\nPast Participial Phrase \n\nPast participles in English take the same form as a verb in the simple past tense. \n\nThese are typically verbs that end in \"-ed,\" or \"-d.\" \n\nExamples: \n\n\"Cracked from top to bottom,\" the mirror was now ruined. \n\n\"Attacked by a bear,\" the man went home with bad injuries.</string>

    <string name="syntax_six_instruction">Clauses are essential components of sentences, and mastering them is crucial for developing strong writing skills. \n\nIn this lesson, we will cover the basics of independent and dependent clauses, various types of dependent clauses, and how to use them in sentences. \n\nBy the end of this workbook, you\'ll be able to craft more complex and engaging sentences. \n\nLet\'s get started! \n\nA clause is a group of words that contains a subject and a verb. \n\nIt can either stand alone as a complete thought (independent clause) or rely on another clause to make sense (dependent clause). \n\nEN7G-II-a-1 \nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully. \n\nEN8WC-Id-1.1.6 \nOrganize ideas in one-step word, phrase, and sentence outline forms.</string>
    <string name="Clauses_Main">Main Clauses \n\nExamples: \n\n\"I love reading books.\" \n\n\"He played basketball.\" \n\nMain clauses are clauses that can stand alone as complete sentences. \n\nIn the first example, \"I love reading books,\" the complete subject (\"I\") and the complete predicate (\"love reading books\") create a complete thought that can be a sentence on its own. \n\nThe same applies to the second example, \"He played basketball.\"</string>
    <string name="Clauses_Subordinating">Subordinating Clauses \n\nSubordinating clauses are clauses that cannot stand alone as complete sentences. \n\nExamples: \n\"Although it rained\" \n\"Because she was tired\" \n\nIn the first example, \"Although it rained,\" we have the subordinating conjunction \"Although\" that makes it a dependent clause. \n\nIt needs more information to complete the thought. \n\nThe second example, \"Because she was tired,\" also relies on additional information to make sense as it starts with the subordinating conjunction “Because.” \n\nTypes of Subordinating Clauses \n\n1. Adjective Clauses \n\nProvide additional information about nouns in sentences. \n\nExamples: \n\"The book that I borrowed from the library is fascinating.\" \n\"The girl who won the race is my sister.\" \n\nIn the first example, \"that I borrowed from the library\"\ describes which book we\'re talking about. \n\nIn the second example, \"who won the race\" provides more information about the girl. \n\nThese clauses function like adjectives, adding details to the nouns they modify. \n\n2. Adverbial Clauses \n\nModify verbs, adjectives, or adverbs. \n\nExamples: \n\"She studied hard because she wanted to pass the exam.\" \n\"He ran quickly so that he could catch the bus.\" \n\nIn the first example, \"because she wanted to pass the exam\" explains why she studied hard, modifying the verb \"studied.\" \n\nIn the second example, \"so that he could 	catch the bus\" tells us the purpose of running quickly, modifying the verb \"ran.\" \n\n3. Noun Clause \n\nA clause (a group of words with a subject and a verb) that serves as a noun in a sentence. \n\nIt is a dependent clause and cannot function alone as a complete sentence. \n\nTo work properly, it must be part of a larger sentence to form a complete thought. \n\nIn other words, a noun clause has a subject and a predicate, like a sentence, but 	because it is dependent, it doesn’t express a complete thought. \n\nA Noun clause usually begins with words such as \"what,\" \"why,\" \"who,\" \"when,\" 	\"how,\" or \"that,\" and can be used to provide more information about a noun in the sentence. \n\nExamples: \n\nMy mom helped me decide which school should I enroll in. \n\nThe most wonderful thing I admired about my teachers is that they are so brilliant. \n\nWhat my parent said helped me to become the person I am now.</string>
    <string name="Clauses_Adjective">Examples: \n\n\"The book that I borrowed from the library is fascinating.\" \n\n\"The girl who won the race is my sister.\" \n\nAdjective clauses provide additional information about nouns in sentences. \n\nIn the first example, \"that I borrowed from the library\" describes which book we\'re talking about. \n\nIn the second example, \"who won the race\" provides more information about the girl. \n\nThese clauses function like adjectives, adding details to the nouns they modify.</string>
    <string name="Clauses_Adverbial">Examples: \n\n\"She studied hard because she wanted to pass the exam.\" \n\n\"He ran quickly so that he could catch the bus.\" \n\nAdverbial clauses modify verbs, adjectives, or adverbs. \n\nIn the first example, \"because she wanted to pass the exam\" explains why she studied hard, modifying the verb \"studied.\" \n\nIn the second example, \"so that he could catch the bus\" tells us the purpose of running quickly, modifying the verb \"ran.\"</string>
    <string name="Clauses_Noun">Noun clauses \n\nIt is a clause (a group of words with a subject and a verb) that serves as a noun in a sentence. \n\nIt is a subordinate clause and cannot function alone as a complete sentence. \n\n\"To work properly\", it must be part of a larger sentence to form a complete thought. \n\nIn other words, a noun clause has a subject and a predicate, like a sentence, but because it is subordinating clause, it doesn\’t express a complete thought. \n\nA Noun clause usually begins with words such as \"what,\" \"why,\" \"who,\" \"when,\" \"how,\" or \"that,\" and can be used to provide more information about a noun in the sentence.
        \n\nExamples:
		\n\nMy mom helped me decide which school should I enroll in.
		\n\nThe most wonderful thing I admired about my teachers is that they are so brilliant.
		\n\nWhat my parent said helped me to become the person I am now.
    </string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_instruction">Understanding subject-verb agreement is a fundamental skill in English grammar. \n\nThe subject and verb in a sentence must agree in number (singular or plural). \n\nThis lesson will cover the rules and exceptions of subject-verb agreement. \n\nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully \nEN7G-II-a-1 \n\nObserve correct subject-verb agreement \nEN7G-I-a-11 \n\nUse parallel structures \nEN8G-Ia-7</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_one">Rule 1: Singular Subjects \n\nWhen the subject of a sentence is singular (referring to one person, place, thing, or idea), the verb must also be singular, typically ending in \"s\" in the third person singular (he, she, it). \n\nExample: \n\nShe writes every day. \n\nIn this sentence, \"She\" is the singular subject, referring to one person. The singular verb \"writes\" agrees with the subject. \n\nException: \n\nWhen using the singular \"they,\" use plural verb forms. \n\nExample: \n\nThe participant expressed satisfaction with their job. They are currently in a managerial role at the organization. \n\n\"They\" is a singular pronoun used in a gender-neutral context. However, it still requires a plural verb form (\"are\").</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_two">Rule 2: Plural Subjects \n\nPlural subjects refer to more than one person, place, thing, or idea. \n\nThey require 	plural verbs, which do not end in \"s\" in the third person plural (they). \n\nExample: \n\nThey write every day. \n\n\"They\" is the plural subject, referring to multiple people. The plural verb \"write\" agrees with the subject.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_three">Rule 3: Compound Subjects \n\nWhen the subject of the sentence is composed of two or more nouns or pronouns connected by \"and,\" use a plural verb. \n\nExample: \n\nThe math student and the committee members write every day. \n\nBoth \"math student\" and \"committee members\" are part of the subject, and they are 	connected by \"and.\" Since it\'s a compound subject, a plural verb \"write\" is used.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_four">Rule 4: Subject-Verb Agreement with Phrases in Between \n\nWhen a phrase comes between the subject and the verb, remember that the verb still agrees with the subject, not the noun or pronoun in the phrase following the subject of the sentence. \n\nExample: \n\nThe student, as well as the committee members, is excited. \n\nEven though there is a phrase \"as well as the committee members\" between the subject \"The student\" and the verb, the verb still agrees with the singular subject \"The 	student.\"</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_five">Rule 5: Singular Nouns or Pronouns Connected by \"or\" or \"nor\" \n\nWhen two or more singular nouns or pronouns are connected by \"or\" or \"nor,\" use a singular verb. \n\nExample: \n\nThe chairperson or the CEO approves the proposal before proceeding. \n\nBoth \"chairperson\" and \"CEO\" are singular nouns connected by \"or,\" so a singular verb \"approves\" is used.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_six">Rule 6: Rule of Proximity (Compound Subject with Singular and Plural) \n\nWhen a compound subject contains both a singular and a plural noun or pronoun 	joined by \"or\" or \"nor,\" the verb should agree with the part of the subject that is closest to 	the verb. This is also called the rule of proximity. \n\nExample 1: \n\nThe student or the committee members write every day. \n\n\"Committee members\" is plural, but since \"student\" is closer to the verb \"write,\" a plural verb is used. \n\nExample 2: \n\nThe committee members or the student writes every day. \n\nIn this case, \"student\" is closer to the verb \"writes,\" which is singular.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_seven">Rule 7: Indefinite Pronouns \n\nWords like \"each,\" \"everyone,\" \"nobody,\" etc., are singular and require a singular verb. \n\nExample: \nEach of the participants was willing to be recorded. \n\n\"Each\" is an indefinite pronoun, and it is singular. Therefore, the singular verb \"was\" is used.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_eight">Rule 8: Noncount Nouns \n\nNoncount nouns take a singular verb. These are nouns that represent something that cannot be counted as individual units. \n\nExample: \n\nEducation is the key to success. \n\n\"Education\" is a noncount noun, and it is treated as singular. Therefore, the singular verb \"is\" is used.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_nine">Rule 9: Nouns with Only Plural Form \n\nSome countable nouns like \"earnings,\" \"goods,\" etc., only have a plural form and take a plural verb. \n\nExample: \n\nThe earnings for this quarter exceed expectations. \n\n\"Earnings\" is a noun that only has a plural form. Therefore, the plural verb \"exceed\" 	is used.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_ten">Rule 10: Sentences Beginning with \"There is\" or \"There are\" \n\nIn sentences beginning with \"there is\" or \"there are,\" the verb agrees with what 	follows the verb, not with \"there.\" \n\nExample: \n\nThere is little administrative support. \n\nThe subject is \"little administrative support,\" which is singular.</string>
    <string name="syntax_seven_eleven">Rule 11: Collective Nouns \n\nCollective nouns, which imply more than one person but are considered singular, take a singular verb. \n\nExample: \n\nThe group meets every week. \n\n\"Group\" is a collective noun and is treated as singular. Therefore, the singular verb \"meets\" is used.</string>
    <string name="morph_one_instruction">Morphemes are the smallest units of meaning in a language. \n\nThey can be words themselves or parts of words (prefixes, suffixes, and roots) that carry meaning. \n\nUnderstanding morphemes is crucial for building vocabulary and grasping the structure of words in a language. \n\nEN8V-IIIa-15.3 \nExplain the meaning of a word through structural analysis (prefixes, roots, suffixes).</string>

    <string name="Free_Morphemes">Free Morphemes \n\nThese are morphemes of independent existence. \n\nThey have morphological unit whose existence are not dependent on any other unit whether morphological, phonological or syntactic as they occur unattached. \n\nThey are words by themselves or the meaning carrying units. \n\nThey are also called the base, root and at times, the stem. \n\nAs the base, root and stem, they can accept other morphemes to be attached to them. \n\nExample: \ngreen \nbig \ndesire \naccept \nstyle</string>

    <string name="Bound_Morphemes">Bound Morphemes \n\nThese are morphemes that cannot stand on their own, but rather must be attached to other morphemes to convey meaning. \n\nTheir major functions are to derive new words in which case they may change the grammatical class of the word and to provide additional grammatical information. \n\nAll these bound morphemes are regarded as affixes in which they occur at the beginning and at the end of a word. \n\nThey are called prefixes when they appear at the beginning of a word, and they are called suffixes when they appear at the end of the word. \n\nExamples: \n\n\Prefix: \n\nun- + happy = unhappy \ndis- + honest = dishonest \nim- + possible = impossible \n\nSuffix: \n\ntea + -s = teas \nwork + -ing = working \ntest + -ed = tested \nslow + -ly = slowly</string>


    <string name="Inflectional_Morphemes">Inflectional Morphemes \n\nThese are affixes that are added to words to convey grammatical information, such as tense, number, case, or comparison. \n\nThey don\'t change the core meaning of the word but provide crucial grammatical details. \n\nThey also close the building of a new word. \n\nBeing the suffix, they come last element in the word. \n\nThere are 8 inflectional Morphemes. \n\nVerb: \n\nSuffix: -s \nFunction: 3rd person singular \nExamples: talks, walks, blinks \n\nSuffix: -d/-ed \nFunction	: simple past \nExamples: talked, walked, blinked \n\nSuffix: -ing \nFunction: present participle \nExamples: talking, walking, blinking \n\n Suffix: -en/ed_2 \nFunction: past participle \nExamples: talked, waled, blinked \n\nNoun: \n\nSuffix: -s \nFunction: plural \nExamples: teams, dogs, students \n\nSuffix: -s’ \nFunction: possessive \nExamples: team’s, dog’s, student’s \n\nAdjective: \n\nSuffix: -er \nFunction: comparative \nExamples: taller, bigger, smarter \n\nSuffix: -est \nFunction: superlative \nExamples: tallest, biggest, smartest</string>

    <string name="Derivational_Morphemes">Derivational Morphemes \n\nThese are affixes that are used in the creation of words. \n\nThey are bound morphemes attached 	to roots to derive new words. \n\nWhen attached to roots, they may either be class changing or class maintaining affixes, they do not close off the building of a new word and they can pile up and may take an inflectional morpheme. \n\nDerivational morphemes create new words that enrich the lexicon of the language. \n\nThey are very productive in the creation of lexical 	morphemes; nouns, verbs, adjectives and adverbs. \n\nClass changing: \n\nVerb          >          Noun \nbreak > breaker \nwash > washer \nwrite > writer \neat > eater \n\nVerb          >          Adjective \naccept > acceptable \ndo > doable \nsell > sellable \nwork > workable \n\nClass maintaining: \n\nNoun          >          Noun \nking > kingdom \nfan > fandom \ndrop > droplet \nbook > booklet \nfather > fatherhood \nmother > motherhood \ncartoon > cartoonist \n\nBuilding of a new word: \n\nvocal + ize= vocalize \nunderstand + able= understandable \ncreate + ive= creative \nhope + ful= hopeful \ncare + less= careless \n\nPiling up of morphemes: \n\nsterile + ize + er + s= sterilizers \nmaterial + ize + ing= materializing \ncreate + ion + s= creations</string>

    <string name="Prefixes">Prefixes \n\nThese are affixes (word parts added to the beginning of words) that change the meaning of a word. \n\nThey often indicate negation, direction, time, or degree. \n\nPrefix: un- \nFunction: it indicates negation or reverses the meaning of a word \nExamples: unblock, unlock, unreal \n\nPrefix: re- \nFunction: it denotes repetition or reversal \nExamples: rewrite, resend, regain \n\nPrefix: pre- \nFunction: it indicates before or in advance \nExamples: preheat, preview, preregistration \n\nPrefix: inter- \nFunction: it indicates the direction or position \nExamples: international, interconnected, intersection</string>
    <string name="Suffixes">Suffixes \n\nThese are affixes that are added to the end of words, altering their meaning or grammatical category. \n\nThey can turn verbs into nouns, create adjectives, and more. \n\nSuffix: -ly \nFunction: this suffix is used to create adverbs \nExamples: hastily, actively, sadly \n\nSuffix: -er \nFunction: it can turn verbs into nouns, indicating a person who performs an action \nExamples: leader, seller, toaster \n\nSuffix: -able \nFunction: it forms adjectives meaning \"capable of” \nExamples: teachable, huggable, scalable \n\nSuffix: -ize \nFunction: used to create verbs \nExamples: visualize, verbalize, actualize	</string>
    <string name="Roots">Roots \n\nThese are the core part of a word that carries its central meaning. \n\nPrefixes and suffixes are added to roots to create more complex words. \n\nRoot: act \nFunction: this root means to do or perform \nExamples: activate, actual, activity \n\nRoot: friend \nFunction: this refers to a person with whom one has a bond \nExamples: friendship, friendly, befriend \n\nRoot: nation \nFunction: this indicates a community of people with shared characteristics \nExamples: international, nationalism, nationhood \n\nRoot: cred \nFunction: this means believe \nExamples: credentials, incredible, accredit \n\nRoot: dict \nFunction: this means speak \nExamples: dictate, dictator, contradict</string>

    <string name="morph_two_instruction">Word formation is the process of creating new words or changing the form of existing words in a language. \n\nIt plays a crucial role in expanding vocabulary and expressing ideas effectively. \n\nEN7RC-IV-b12.3 \nUse lexical and contextual cues in understanding unfamiliar words and expressions. \n\nEN8V-Ie-4 \nUse appropriate strategies in unlocking the meaning of unfamiliar words and idiomatic expressions. \n\nEN8V-IIIa-15.3 \nExplain the meaning of a word through structural analysis (prefixes, roots, suffixes). \n\nEN8V-IIId-25 \nUse appropriate strategies for unlocking unfamiliar words. \n\nEN8V-IIIe-12.3 \nArrive at meanings through context clues. \n\nEN9V-Ie-11 \nArrive at meaning of words through word formation (clipping, blending, acronym, compounding, folk etymology, etc.)</string>
    <string name="Compounding">Compounding \n\nIt is created by joining free morphemes together to make a new word with a distinct 	meaning. \n\nRemember that a free morpheme is a morpheme that can stand alone. \n\nExamples: \n\nBedroom is formed by combining \"bed\" and \"room\" \n\nToothpaste is formed by combining \"tooth\" and \"paste\"</string>
    <string name="Blending">Blending \n\nIt involves taking two or more words, removing parts of each, and joining the residues together to create a new word whose form and meaning are taken from the source words. \n\nExamples: \n\nBrunch blends \"breakfast\" and \"lunch\" \n\nSmog blends \"smoke\" and \"fog\"</string>
    <string name="Backformation">Backformation \n\nIt is also called back–derivation, is a type of word formation process which involves creating a new word from an existing word by reducing an affix or some part of the root to form a new part of speech. \n\nExamples: \n\nEdit is a backform from editor by removing the suffix \"-or\" \n\nForm is a backform from formal by removing the suffix \"-al\" \n\nTranslate is a backform from translation by removing the suffix \"-ion\"</string>
    <string name="Conversion">Conversion \n\nIt is another type of word formation process which is also called zero derivation or null derivation. \n\nConversion involves creating a word with a new word class without any change in its structure. \n\nExamples: \n\nEmail can be a noun (I received an email) or a verb (I will email you). \n\nText can be a noun (I received a text) or a verb (I will text you).</string>

    <string name="morph_two_seven">Conversion changes the grammatical category of a word without adding or removing affixes. \n\nExamples \nEmail can be a noun (I received an email) or a verb (I will email you). \nText can be a noun (I received a text) or a verb (I will text you).</string>
    <string name="seven_5">Rule 5: Singular Nouns or Pronouns Connected by \"or\" or \"nor\"</string>
    <string name="seven_10">Rule 10: Sentences Beginning with \"There is\" or \"There are\"</string>
    <string name="instruction_rearange">Instructions: Rearrange the words in correct order to make complete sentences. e.g. \nthe fat cat / a mouse / is chasing. \nThe fat cat is chasing a mouse.</string>
</resources>