<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="syntax_phrases_instruction">Welcome to the \"Exploring Phrases\" lesson! \n\nPhrases are essential building blocks of sentences, and a good grasp of phrases can greatly improve your writing and communication skills. \n\nA phrase is a group of related words that does not contain a subject and a predicate (verb and its accompanying elements) necessary for a complete sentence. \n\nPhrases function as units within sentences and can serve various grammatical roles. Phrases come in different types, including noun phrases, verb phrases, adjective phrases, and adverb phrases, each with its specific role and structure in a sentence. \n\nEN7G-II-a-1 \nUse phrases, clauses, and sentences appropriately and meaningfully. \n\nEN8WC-Id-1.1.6 \nOrganize ideas in one-step word, phrase, and sentence outline forms.
    </string>

    <string name="syntax_phrases_noun">Noun Phrase \n\nA word or group of words in a sentence that behaves in the same way as a noun, that is, as a subject, an object, a complement, or as the object of a preposition. \n\nExamples: \n\n1. \“A dark smoke scattered across the sky.\” In this sentence, the noun phrase \“A dark smoke\” is functioning as the subject of the sentence. \n\n2. \“He spoke like an angel.\” In this sentence, the noun phrase \“like an angel\” is an adverbial, because it functions as an adverb, describing how he spoke. \n\n3. \“The boxer threw a killing punch.\” Here, \“a killing punch\” is a noun phrase that functions as a direct object, being the thing that the boxer (the subject) threw (the verb). \n\n4. \“I baked my little brother a cake.\” The noun phrase \“my little brother\” is the indirect object of the sentence, as it is affected by the verb but not the direct object of the verb, which is \“a cake.\” \n\n5. \“They both stayed in the top with exemplary marks.\” In this sentence, the noun phrase \“in the top\” works as a prepositional phrase, because the noun \“top\” is modified by the preposition \“in.\” \n\n6. \“Some students lost their interest in doing well with their studies.\” The noun phrase \“some students\” is a noun plus a determiner, meaning that the word \“some\” determines something essential about the noun. In this case, it is a specific kind of determiner known as a quantifier, because it is revealing how many students lost their interest.
    </string>

    <string name="syntax_phrases_verb">Verb Phrase \n\nA combination of words that express an action or a state of being. It typically consists of a main verb and one or more auxiliary verbs. It also may include other words, such as adverbs and nouns. Verb phrases are used to express complex ideas, such as opinions, feelings, and wishes. \n\nTypes of Verb Phrases \n\n1. Verb phrases with only the main verb \n\nWhen we hear the word \'phrase\', we expect the inclusion of more than one word; however, this isn\'t always the case! Verb phrases can be a singular main verb on its own. \n\nExamples: \n\nShe \"breaks\" her leg. \n\nThey both \"screamed.\" \n\nIn these examples, the verb phrase consists of a main verb only. The verb can be in the present or past tense. The first example is in the present tense and the second one is in the past tense. \n\nAuxiliary verb (to be) + main verb (-ing form) \n\nWhen the main verb is being used in its -ing form (e.g. walking, talking), it expresses a continuous aspect. The use of auxiliary verbs will show whether the continuing action is in the past, present, or future. \n\nThe auxiliary verbs \"am\", \"is\", and \"are\" used before the main verb in \'-ing\' form creates the \"present continuous tense.\" \n\nThe auxiliary verbs was and were used before the main verb in \'-ing\' form creates the \"past continuous tense.\" \n\nThe combined auxiliary verbs \'will be\' used before the main verb in \'-ing\' form creates the \"future continuous tense.\" \n\nExamples: \nShe \"is staring\" at the window. \n\nThe students \"were writing\" their stories. \n\nJoan \"will be coming\" next day. \n\n3. Auxiliary verb (have) + main verb (past participle form) \n\nThis type of verb phrase includes the verb \'to have\' (including all of its forms e.g. have, has, had) and the past participle form of the main verb. \n\nPast participle verb forms are also referred to as verb 3. They are most commonly used to show the perfect aspect, a verb form that shows an action is either completed or begun in the past. The perfect aspect tends to focus more on the state of the action (i.e. whether or not it has been completed) rather than the action itself. For example, \'It had just begun\' lets the listener know that the happening recently just begun. The verbs \"have\" and \"has\" express a \"present perfect aspect\", whereas the verb \"had\" expresses a \"past perfect aspect.\" \n\nExamples: \n\nClaire had just slept for more than an hour. \n\nThe team has won the competition. \n\nRico had broken the window. \n\n4. Modal verb + main verb \n\nModal verbs are a type of auxiliary verb that express modality. Modality includes 	things 	such as possibility, probability, ability, permission, ability, and obligation. Example 	modal verbs include: must, shall, will, should, would, can, could, may, and might. \n\nExamples: \n\nHe \"will join\" the singing contest. \n\nJess \"might deliver\" his speech later. \n\n5. Auxiliary verb (have + been) + main verb (-ing form) \n\nIn this case, both the continuous aspect and the perfect aspect are expressed. The 	continuous aspect comes from the \'-ing\' verb, and the perfect aspect comes from the auxiliary verb \'have been\'. When the auxiliary verb \"has\" or \"have\" is used, it creates the \"present perfect continuous aspect\". When the auxiliary verb \"had\" is used, it expresses a \"past perfect continuous aspect.\" \n\nExamples: \n\nKrisha \"has been writing\" her poem. \n\nThe students \"had been reciting\" their speech.
    </string>

    <string name="syntax_phrases_prepositional">Prepositional Phrase \n\n A prepositional phrase is a group of words that begins with a preposition (like \"under,\" \"in,\" or \"on\") and tells us more about the location of a noun or pronoun. \n\nIt is a combination of a preposition, a modifier and its object. A prepositional phrase can be placed in the beginning, middle or end of a sentence based on its role in that particular sentence. Prepositional phrases are just a part of the sentence it modifies and cannot stand alone. There are a few points you have to keep in mind when using prepositional phrases. They are: \n\n> Each sentence would require a different preposition to form a prepositional phrase. \n\n> Remember that using a wrong preposition can alter the meaning of the sentence completely and sometimes make no meaning at all. \n\n> If the prepositional phrase modifies a noun, it functions like an \"adjective\" and is therefore considered as an \"adjectival phrase.\" \n\n> Sometimes, a prepositional phrase is seen to modify the \"verb\" or action in the sentence and is considered as an \"adverbial phrase\" as it plays the role of an \"adverb\" in the sentence. \n\nExamples: \n\n\'Using Prepositional Phrases in the Beginning of the Sentence\' \n\n\"After sleeping for hours,\" Marina finally got the rest that her body wanted. \n\n\"Before the athletes start training,\" they would first conduct warm-up activities. \n\n\'Using Prepositional Phrases in the Middle of the Sentence\' \n\nThe man \"in the photograph\" is the one whom he was looking for. \n\nThe red bag \"on the cabinet\" was her favorite one. \n\n\'Using Prepositional Phrases in the End of the Sentence\' \n\nThe key was placed \"on the table.\" \n\nThey cut the tree \"beside our house.\"
    </string>

    <string name="syntax_phrases_adjectival">Adjectival Phrase \n\nA prepositional phrase that modifies noun or pronoun. \n\nExamples: \n\nThe students \"on that section\" are very noisy. \n\nThis cafe \"beside the mall\" has a good tasting coffee.
    </string>

    <string name="syntax_phrases_adverbial">Adverbial Phrase \n\nA prepositional phrase that modifies a verb, an adjective or an adverb. \n\nExamples:\n\nThe lady looks too chic \"on her dress.\" \n\nThe boy sat \"under the tree.\"
    </string>

    <string name="syntax_phrases_infinitive">Infinitive Phrase An infinitive phrase begins with the infinitive verb, usually with the word \"to\" in front. The position of the infinitive phrase depends on the role it assumes in the sentence. If the infinitive phrase displays the characteristics of a noun, it can be placed either in the beginning or end of the sentence. In other words, it can either be the subject or the object of the sentence. If the infinitive phrase performs as an adjective, it is most often placed just after the verb, and if it shows the characteristics of an adverb, it can be positioned in different parts of the sentence. \n\nFunctions of the Infinitive Phrase \n\nWhen an infinitive phrase functions as a \"noun\", it can be a subject, an object, or a complement. \n\nExamples: \n\n\"To win the contest\" was Kian’s only wish. \n\nHis only task was \"to feed the chicken every morning.\" \n\nInfinitive phrases can also act as \"adjectives.\" An adjective describes or modifies a noun. \n\nExamples: \n\nI’m painting some landmarks \"to present on the exhibit.\" \n\nEvery day, Rico has the determination \"to do well in school.\" \n\nFinally, infinitive phrases can act like \"adverbs\" and modify a verb. Usually, when an infinitive phrase is functioning as an adverb, it explains the why of the verb. \n\nExamples: \n\nTrixie excels in school \"to make her parents proud.\" \n\nAhead of time, teacher Love prepared her lesson \"to avoid cramming.\"
    </string>

    <string name="syntax_phrases_participial">Participial Phrase \n\nA collection of words that begins with a present or past participle and functions as 	an adjective. In simpler terms, it\'s a phrase that describes a noun or pronoun. There are two kinds of participial phrases: Present participial phrases that use the present participle (-ing) form of a verb, and the past participial phrases that use the past participle (-d/-ed) form of a verb. \n\nPresent Participial Phrase \n\nIn English, present participles take the form of verbs ending in \"-ing.\" This is the same form that verbs take in the present progressive tense. \n\nExamples: \n\n\"Talking about the incident,\" she said that she was not well aware of what exactly had happened. \n\n\"Fond of putting make up,\" the girl looked funny. \n\nPast Participial Phrase \n\nPast participles in English take the same form as a verb in the simple past tense. These are typically verbs that end in \"-ed,\" or \"-d.\" \n\nExamples: \n\n\"Cracked from top to bottom,\" the mirror was now ruined. \n\n\"Attacked by a bear,\" the man went home with bad injuries.
    </string>

</resources>